Romania Subject Files, Inclusive: 1936-2008, undated, Bulk: 1974-1991
Baylor University, The Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society
Romania Subject Files
Inclusive: 1936-2008, undated, Bulk: 1974-1991
Baylor University, The Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society http://www.baylor.edu/kestoncenter/
4
Keston Institute, 1969 -
38 A4 document boxes
The Romania Subject Files contain a variety of materials on religious persecution, state religious policies, communist ideology, atheist propaganda, discrimination of ethnic minorities, and human rights activity in the country.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Average.
Biography/Profile
Keston College, originally founded in 1969 as the Center for the Study of Religion and Communism with the named changed to Keston College in 1974, collected and publicized details about religious persecution behind the Iron Curtain, becoming “the voice of the voiceless.” After the collapse of communism in the 1990s, Keston College moved to Oxford and downsized due to decreased funding. The name eventually changed to Keston Institute. In 2007, the Institute transferred the Keston Archive and Library to the newly created Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society at Baylor University.
Keston collected, verified, translated, and disseminated information received from believers in the Soviet Union, Poland, Romania, Czechoslovakia, Hungary, Yugoslavia, Bulgaria and other communist countries. The Keston Archive and Library housed numerous letters, petitions, reports and underground publications (Samizdat) from believers of various denominations along with officially published books and periodicals.
From the beginning of the post-World War II period until approximately 2007, Keston obtained materials documenting the religious and political climate and persecution in Romania, a country which suffered under the communist dictatorship from 1947 to 1989.
Romania in the World War II
Romania began World War II on Nazi Germany’s side, but joined the Allies in 1944 after a King Michael led coup toppled the fascist regime of Ion Antoniescu. The overthrow accelerated the Soviet Army’s advance into the country. In September 1944, the United States, Great Britain and the Soviet Union signed a military armistice with Romania, and Romanian armed forces fought alongside the Red Army to liberate the country. In spite of recognizing Romania as joining the Allies by the end of the War, the 1947 Paris Peace Conference nevertheless treated the country as a Nazi ally. Romania remained under Soviet occupation from 1944 to 1958, and the Soviet Union maintained a significant military presence in the country.
Creation of the Socialist Republic of Rumania
By 1946, Communists had become a dominant political force in Romania. Party leader Gheorghe Gheorghiu-Dej, a devoted Stalinist, persecuted all opposition. In 1947, Communists declared the formation of the People’s Republic of Romania, forcing King Michael into abdication and exile. The Communists nationalized all private businesses and collectivized all agriculture. Gheorghiu-Dej adopted Stalin’s model of industrialization, bringing the economy to the pre-war level by 1950.
In 1948, the regime began inculcating “socialist” values and rewrote the history of Romania to highlight Russia’s contributions and redefine national identity by brushing over Western roots and stressing Slavic influence. The government ordered writers and artists to embrace socialist realism. The regime jailed many intellectuals and teachers, transformed the Romanian Orthodox Church into a government-controlled organization, supervised Roman Catholic schools, imprisoned Catholic clergy, seized Uniate church property, restricted Jewish religious observances, and harassed Jewish believers. Soviet authorities provided guidance for creation of the Securitate, a Romanian secret police. The Romanian government curtailed political liberty and suppressed dissent with Securitate assistance.
After Stalin’s death, Gheorghe Georgiu-Dej advocated national self-determination and launched “national” Communism. He opposed Romania providing resources for the Soviet Union and strengthened economic ties with the West and China. In 1955, Romania joined the Warsaw Pact but later refused to allow maneuvers on its soil and limited participation in the alliance’s military training elsewhere. In 1958, Georgiu-Dej ended Soviet military presence in Romania and remained head of the Romanian government until his death in 1965.
Communism
Nicolae Ceausescu, the first secretary of the Romanian Communist Party, became the Communist Romanian dictator in 1965. He implemented reforms at the beginning of his rule that allowed more freedom and positively affected the economy. Ceausescu preached “national” Communism and widened Romania’s divergence from Soviet policies. He denounced the Soviet Union for ordering the Warsaw Pact invasion of Czechoslovakia, recognized the Federal Republic of Germany, and maintained diplomatic relationships with Israel.
However, Ceausescu’s nearly two decades of supremacy became the most gruesome in Romanian history. Ceausescu consolidated his power by introducing “dynastic” socialism, implementing “rotation of cadres” in the government, and exploiting a ruthlessly efficient secret police. He continued forceful “Romanization” which led to severe discrimination of ethnic minorities. He pursued a singular agenda in economics and foreign policy which resulted in financial crisis, enormous foreign debt, and shortages of food, electricity and other consumer goods. To repay the debt, Ceausescu introduced draconian measures to reduce imports and maximize export earnings. For the first time since the early postwar years, the government imposed food rationing in order to export agricultural products for foreign currency. Electricity, gasoline, and heat were also rationed. By the time the debt was repaid in 1989, the country was on the edge of collapse and its population exhausted.
In an attempt to boost Romanian economy in the early 1970s, Ceausescu launched a program to “systematize” the countryside by destroying “nonviable” villages and building agro-industrial centers. Many “qualifying” villages with populations of less than 3,000 were ancient Hungarian and German settlements.
Continuous violations of basic human rights by Ceausescu’s regime damaged Romania’s foreign relations, not just with the West but also with the rest of the Warsaw Pact. The United States, West Germany, and Israel protested Romania’s increasingly restrictive immigration policies. Treatment of the Transylvania Hungarian community by Ceausescu’s regime caused inflamed relations with Hungary. An attempt to assimilate German and Hungarian national minorities into Romanian society resulted in severe cultural discrimination.
The 1989 Revolution
In December 1989, residents of Transylvania protested against persecution of a young Hungarian pastor, Lazlo Tokes, for openly criticizing the Securitate for lack of freedom. Inspired by democratic changes occurring elsewhere in Europe, protests quickly spread from Temisoara to Bucharest and throughout the country, resulting in the fall of Ceausescu. A military tribunal tried Nicolae and Elena Ceausescu for “crimes against the people” and sentenced them to death. Among the Eastern European revolutions which brought Communism to an end, the Romanian revolution stood as the most violent.
Post-Communism
The National Salvation Front (NSF), the governing body of Romania after the fall of the Ceausescu regime, won the spring 1990 election. Its leader and former Romanian Communist Party member Ion Iliescu became Romania’s second president. By the end of 1990, Iliescu’s government failed to implement efficient economic reforms, escalated interethnic tensions, and emigrated large numbers of ethnic Hungarians and Germans. The international community continually criticized the regime for using force to suppress dissent. Despite pressure, Iliescu’s government prosecuted only a small number of former secret police. NSF reorganized the Securitate into the Romanian Intelligence Service and reemployed many of its former members. Securitate archives remained closed until 2000. However, two of the largest parties in Romania, the Social Democratic Party and the National Liberal Party, emerged from the NSF.
Scope and Content
Romania subject files consist of newspaper clippings, bibliographic references, handwritten notes, correspondence, research papers, manuscripts, church and secular publications, reports on issues of religion and atheism and religious dissidents in Romania, and Romanian Samizdat (underground publications).
The materials cover a period from 1936 to 2008 with the bulk from 1974 to 1991. The most notable topics include, but are not limited to, discrimination of ethnic minorities, Ceausescu’s policy of rural development, and the December 1989 revolution.
Arrangement
The Keston Center received most of the Romania materials in files organized by specific categories and denominations. This original filing system has been preserved. The Romania materials received by the Keston Center in no particular order are arranged thematically and chronologically.
The Romania Subject Files are now arranged into two series: I. General and II. Denominational materials.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to the Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 4.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Ceausescu, Nicolae.
Subjects (Organizations)
Biserica Ortodoxă Română.
Places
Romania -- Church history.; Romania -- Economic conditions -- 1945-1989.; Romania -- Economic conditions -- 1989-; Romania -- Ethnic relations.; Romania -- History -- 1914-1944.; Romania -- History -- 1944-1989.; Romania -- History -- 1989-; Romania -- Politics and government -- 1944-1989.; Romania -- Politics and government -- 1989-; Romania -- Religion.; Romania -- Social conditions.
Subjects
Christians -- Romania.; Church and state -- Romania.; Communism and Christianity -- Romania.; Germans -- Romania.; Human rights -- Romania.; Hungarians -- Romania.; Jews -- Romania.; Minorities -- Romania -- Transylvania.; Persecution -- Romania.; Post-communism -- Romania.; Religion and state -- Romania.; Rural development -- Romania.
Genres
Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Manuscripts.; Samizdat.
- General, 1961-2006, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Biography/Profile
  General Romania subject files contain materials on religious persecution, human rights activity, state religious policies, atheist propaganda, communist ideology and dissident activity.
  - History, 1974-1994, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - History. Pre-Communist Period, 1972- 1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - History. Communist Period, 1965-2006 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - State. Government. Nationhood, 1985-1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - State. Government. Nationhood. Bessarabia, 1966-1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - State. Government. Nationhood. Transylvania (1 of 2), 1968-1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - State. Government. Nationhood. Transylvania (2 of 2), 1987-1999, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Census. Population, 1977-1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - National Identity. Nationalism, 1966-1991, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - National Minorities (1 of 3), 1963-1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - National Minorities (2 of 3), 1980-1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - National Minorities (3 of 3), 1987-1998, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Nationalities policy, 1978-1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Patriotism, 1976-1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Government, 1975-1980 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Government, 1982-1991 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Government Elections, 1979-1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Government Individuals, 1976-1997, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Government Policies, 1977-1988 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - State Administration, 1974-1987 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Military Affairs, 1975-1990 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Espionage, 1975-1987, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Emigration (1 of 2), 1975-1982 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Emigration (2 of 2), 1983-1990, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Constitution, 1965-1991 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Basic Rights & Freedoms, 1976-1990 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Law (1 of 2), 1972-1976 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Law (2 of 2), 1977-1990, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Administration of the Law, 1976-1991 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Crime, 1977-1984 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - State Security Organs, 1976-1998 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Prisons. Labor Camps. Amnesties, 1963-1998, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Oppressive Practices, 1974-1990 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Harassment, 1982-1987 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Physical Assault, 1974-1990 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Fines, 1975-1987 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Interrogations, 1975-1987 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Trials, 1979-1983, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Imprisonment, 1977-1989, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Expulsion of Own Nationals, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Censorship, 1977-1988 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - State Interference in Religious Affairs, 1975-1991 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Discrimination in Employment, 1975-1984 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Psychiatric Institutions, 1973-1986, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - House Searches, 1974-1986 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - International Relations, 1965-1990 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - International Relations with China, 1964-1990 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - International Relations with Eastern Europe, 1975-1989, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - International Relations with France, 1979-1991 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - International Relation with Great Britain, 1973-1997 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - International Relation with Hungary, 1977-1991 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - International Relations with Middle East, 1977-1987 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - International Relations with Soviet Union (1 of 2), 1964-1980 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - International Relations with Soviet Union (2 of 2), 1982-1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - International Relations with United States of America (1 of 2), 1973-1984 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - International Relations with United States of America (2 of 2), 1985-1991, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - International Relations with Vatican, 1965-1999 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - International Relations with Western Europe, 1972-1985 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - General Lines of Foreign Policy, 1973-1989 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Foreigners. Smuggling. Personal Contacts, 1973-1995, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Peaceful Coexistence. Détente. Exchanges, 1970-1987 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Helsinki and Belgrade Conferences, 1973-1989 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Western Reactions. Interventions. Pronouncements, 1963-1989, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - International Incidents, 1979-1986 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Territorial Disputes, 1976-1986 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Contacts with International Organizations, 1969-1989 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Contacts with UN and UN Agencies, 1976-1987 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Contacts with Amnesty International, 1978-1990 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Contacts with Émigré Circles, 1977-1987 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Peace Activities, 1976-1981 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Visits. General, 1975-1988 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Statistics, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Dissidents. Protests. Illegal Activities. General References, 1978-1990 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Individual Dissidents, 1977-1990 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Individual Dissidents. Cornea, Doina, 1988-1990, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Individual Dissidents. Goma, Paul, 1972-1989 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Protests, 1978-1990, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Defense of Human Rights, 1983-1990 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Political Opposition, 1979-1990, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Jokes & Cartoons, 1982-1987 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Defections, 1965-1989 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Contacts with Foreigners, 1984-1988 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Samizdat Publications, 1982-1989 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Terrorism, 1982-1985 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Free Trade Unions (1 of 2), 1977-1987 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Free Trade Unions (2 of 2), undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Nationalist Dissent, 1987-1990 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Dissident Cultural Activity, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Religion (1 of 3), 1967-2003 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Religion (2 of 3), 1987 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Religion (3 of 3), undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Religion. General Interdenominational (1 of 4), 1965-1990, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Religion. General Interdenominational (2 of 4), 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Religion. General Interdenominational (3 of 4), 1977 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Religion. General Interdenominational (4 of 4), 1980 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Church-State Relations, 1973-1990, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Basic Rights and Freedoms, 1972-2001 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Law and Religion (1 of 3), undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Law and Religion (2 of 3), 1964-1999 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Law and Religion ( 3 of 3), 1999, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Department of Religious Cults, 1977-1991 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Oppressive Practices Relating to Religious Activity (1 of 2), 1969-1979 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Oppressive Practices Relating to Religious Activity (2 of 2), 1979-1987, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Discrimination in Education, 1976-1987 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Attacks in Media, 1978-1986 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Loss of Parental Rights, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Religion & Peace, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Christian Peace Conference, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Religion Abroad, 1971-1982, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Religion Abroad. Western Reactions (1 of 2), 1971-1997, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Religion Abroad. Western Reactions (2 of 2), 1971-1997, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Religion Abroad. Romanian Visits Abroad, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Religion Abroad. Interdenominational Visits, 1972-1999 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Religion Abroad. Billy Graham, 1985-1989, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Religion Abroad. Bible Smuggling, 1974-1987 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Religious Publications, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Religious Dissent, 1976-1990 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - The Romanian Christian Committee "The Defense for Religious Liberty and Conscience" (1 of 3), 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - The Romanian Christian Committee "The Defense for Religious Liberty and Conscience" (2 of 3), 1980 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - The Romanian Christian Committee "The Defense for Religious Liberty and Conscience" (3 of 3), 1981-1983, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Religious Revival, 1974-2001, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Religious Sects, 1972-1990, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Religion and Science. Religion and Medicine, 1976-1980, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Communism and Christianity, 1973-1990 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Religion and Official Pronouncements, 1974-1980 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Theological Education, 1980-1990 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Statistics, 1974-1992 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Psychology of Religion, 1976-1980 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Ecumenical Movement (1 of 2), 1969-1998, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Ecumenical Movement (2 of 2), 1966-2001 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Religious Broadcasts, 1984-1998, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Religion and Nationalism, 1976-1989 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Religion and Culture, 1976-1987, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Religion and Intelligentsia, 1977-1991 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Bible. General, 1944-1991, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Church Architecture, 1932-1986, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Religion and Women, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Religion and Youth, 1972-1991 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Religion and Family, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Sociology of Religion (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Atheism, 1976-1991 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - General Atheists Propaganda, 1961-1987 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Atheism in Education, 1976-1977 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Atheism in Youth and Children Organizations, 1971-1987, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Atheism in Press, 1973-1987 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Atheism on Radio and TV, 1976-1987 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Atheist Publications, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Atheist Libraries. Museums. Exhibitions, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - New Traditions, 1976-1977 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Scientific Atheism. Philosophy of Atheism, 1972-1979 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Training in Atheist Work. Atheist Schools. Seminars. Courses, 1973-1987 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Methods of Atheist Work, 1976-1979 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Criticism of Atheist Work, 1976-1987 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Ideology. Communist Ethics. Philosophy. Morality, 1976-1989 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Romanian Communist Party, 1965-1990 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - History of the Romanian Communist Party, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Romanian Communist Party Congress. Decisions (1 of 2), 1974-1979 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Romanian Communist Party Congress. Decisions (2 of 2), 1980-1989, undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Contacts with Other Communist Parties and States, 1971-1980 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Mass Organizations, 1976-1980, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Purges. Ideological Deviations from Party Line, 1976-1989 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Romanian Communist Party Statistics, 1978-1987, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Individual Communists and Ideologists, 1971-2006, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Communism. General, 1965-1977 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Ideology. General (1 of 4), 1973-1976 March (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Ideology. General (2 of 4), 1976 April-June (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Ideology. General (3 of 4), 1976m July-December (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Ideology. General (4 of 4), 1977-1984 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Ideological Propaganda. Work. Education, 1973-1989, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Ideological Differences with Socialist States and Parties, 1966-1989 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Ideological Differences with the West, 1976-1980 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Ideological Propaganda from the West, 1976-1985 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Ideological and Religious Broadcasts from the West, 1971-1987, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Ideological and Religious Broadcasts from the West. Radio Free Europe, 1974-1987, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Ideological Press and Publications in the West, 1978-1987, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Philosophy, 1975-1995 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Ethics, 1976-1978 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Morality, 1970-1984 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Émigrés, 1976-1987 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Ideology in Education, Art, and Culture, 1973-1987, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Agriculture. Economy. Labor, 1964-1988, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Economy (1 of 4), 1972-1979 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Economy (2 of 4), 1980-1983 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Economy (3 of 4), 1984-1985 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Economy (4 of 4), 1986-1991, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Labor, 1976-1989, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Education. Science. Geography, 1976-1990, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Education, 1965-1990, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Natural Disasters (1 of 2), 1972-1977 March (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Natural disasters (2 of 2), 1977 March-1986, undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Ecology, 1987-1990, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Statistics, 1975-1982 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Health. Leisure. Sport. Tourism, 1964-1990, undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Information Services. TV. Radio. Press., 1976-1990 (Box 14, Folder 11)